Addison Okell

SUMMARY

Third Year Mathematical Physics student from the University of Waterloo, with three terms of term distinction and one term of deans honor roll. Excellent analytical skills and experience using Python, Maple, R and LaTex. Experience researching in an academic environment and a member of Rocketry club. An interest in theoretical physics and mathematics.

EDUCATION

University of Waterloo

Bachelor of Science, Mathematical Physics - Major Average - 83.0%

 $09\ 2019 - 04\ 2024$

Waterloo, Ontario

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

- Quantum Mechanics I
- Electricity and Magnetism I & II
- Computational Physics
 - I & II
- Classical Mechanics I & II
- Thermodynamics
- Calculus I-III
- Vector Calculus
- Linear Algebra I & II
- ODE I & II
- Statistics I & II

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

University of Waterloo - Faculty of Engineering

<u>Research Assistant</u>

 $01\ 2022-04\ 2022$

Waterloo, Ontario

- Researching besetting incidents of ships
- Running ice simulations
- Reading remote sensing and satellite data
- Creating plots of the data using Python

Evolution Mining

Student Lab Technician

 $05\ 2022-08\ 2022$

Red Lake, Ontario

- Create a tool in Excel to report accuracy of result
- Write a report on the created tool
- Run assays to find metal content of samples using atomic absorption spectroscopy

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, R, LaTex, Maple

Python Libraries: Matplotlib, Numpy, Pandas, netCDF4

Developer Tools: Anaconda, Jupiter Notebook, Spyder, R Studio, Overleaf, TeXStudio, Maple

Technologies/Frameworks: Linux, Windows, MacOS

AWARDS

- Term Distinction 84.6%
- Term Distinction 86.0%
- Term Distinction 90.5%
- Term Deans Honors List 82.5%
- University of Waterloo Merit Scholarship

EXTRACURRICULAR

UW Rocketry Club

09 2022 - Present

- Analysis for handles for kismet injector valve
- Machining brace for actuation mechanism
- Repairing leaks in valves
- Sourcing parts